<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_description">
		<text>Traditional outfit of a bandit - a leather jacket with kevlar elements. Provides protection highly insufficient for the Zone&apos;s severe conditions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_description_m">
		<text>>Common weak bandit body armor with mail plates sewn in its backing. Almost everyone can do it, but not everyone by far will have enough patience to.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_name_m">
		<text>Mail Jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_description">
		<text>Produced by one of Kiev&apos;s defence research institutes and commissioned by the Duty faction. It is as simple and reliable as the standard PSZ-9 model, but due to the new materials, it provides good protection from various harmful impacts, including firearm damage. The vest still needs some work because it has no breathing protection system.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Duty armor suit with enhanced parameters of protection against bites and cuts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_name">
		<text>PSZ-9d Duty Armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Hunter PSZ-9d</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>A wonderful protective suit for the Zone. Stalkers appreciate it because it combines excellent anomaly-proof and bullet-proof qualities. It includes the PSZ-9d suit, a closed cycle breathing system and an integrated system of anomalous field suppression. It provides quality bullet and splinter protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>PSZ-9Md Universal Protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_outfit_description">
		<text>A SSP-99 chemical protection suit specially designed for the Zone conditions. It is used by scientific expeditions and the eco-stalkers who cooperate with them. It has an integrated air-filtering and air-conditioning system. It is heat and electricity resistant, provides good protection from radiation and biological anomalies. It is resistant to chemically aggressive environments. It is not designed for combat, so it provides neither bullet, nor splinter protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_outfit_name">
		<text>SSP-99 Ecologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_description">
		<text>An experimental sample of a military exoskeleton. In the batch production and did not hit, in view of the extraordinary cost and some errors in the design. In spite of this, it is produced in small batches at underground enterprises in China. This exoskeleton belongs to the third generation. It eliminated design flaws, cardinally reduced mobility, and reinforced armor. Provides excellent protection against bullet and shrapnel hits, but does not guarantee resistance to anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Prototype of a second-generation monolithic exoskeleton with a night vision device with digital signal filtering and a system for protecting against psi radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton PNB-4UZ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_description">
		<text>Stalker suit from the Merc faction. Its design is based on the suit used by the special forces of the Western armies. Due to a special treatment of the fabric, the armor has a strengthened stability during the physical movement of its plates. Its protective properties are slightly better then those of the PSZ-7 military bulletproof suits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>There is chain mail sown into the lining of the coat, which raises the level of protection against firearm attack and monster bites. A PNV is also included in the set.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_name">
		<text>Комбинезон наемника</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Merc suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_description">
		<text>This Skat-9M bulletproof military suit is designed for assault operations in areas of anomalous activity. It includes a PSZ-12p heavy military bulletproof suit, an integrated compensation suit and a Sphere-12M helmet. It provides perfect protection from bullets and splinters and it doesn’t decrease the soldier’s mobility. It has a balanced system of anomaly protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_name">
		<text>Army bulletproof suit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_outfit_description">
		<text>Stalker suit from the Monolith faction. The producer is unknown. Its protective properties are slightly worse then those of the PSZ-9a military bulletproof vest. Its structure is similar to the suit popular with neutral stalkers which combines a bulletproof vest and a radiation protection suit. It provides good protection from gunfire. Its level of anomaly protection is low due to the absence of an air filtering system.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolith suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice_outfit_description_m">
		<text>They took this coat off of the body of one of the stalkers who died in the anomaly &quot;fruit punch&quot;. Having laid a long time in the anomaly, the coat obtained the ability to speed up metabolism.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice_outfit_name_m">
		<text>Skinner anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_soldier_description">
		<text>An ordinary thick jacket, one of the many. It slightly increases bullet and splinter protection. It does not protect from anomalies and other affects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_soldier_name">
		<text>Leather jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="protection_outfit_description">
		<text>High quality modified SSP-99 suit. It provides increased body protection from bullet and splinter damage. It is designed for the guards working with scientific expeditions. It provides good protection from radiation and biological anomalies. It is resistant to chemically aggressive environments and other effects dangerous to the body.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="protection_outfit_name">
		<text>SSP-99M suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This suit was produced by one of Kiev&apos;s defence research institutes and represents an excellent alternative to stalker hand-made suits. It is an excellent combination of an bulletproof vest, a closed cycle breathing system and an integrated system of anomalous field suppression. Due to the perfect choice of the materials, it is a good choice. The only disadvantage is its price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>SEVA suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specnaz_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>The fabric of the suit is saturated with a streptozoidal lotion, which speeds up the healing of wounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specnaz_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Healing Beril</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specops_outfit_description">
		<text>A Berill-5M special forces suit modified for the Zone environment. It includes a PSZ-9a military bulletproof vest with beryllium coating and a Sphere-08 helmet. It is designed for assault operations in areas with high background radiation. Its level of anomaly protection is low.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specops_outfit_name">
		<text>Berill-5M armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_description">
		<text>Produced by &quot;folk craftsmen,&quot; the stalker&apos;s overall is an effective combination of light army body armor and overalls made of rubberized fabric. Enhanced due to built-in Kevlar plates. Good protection against weak small arms. In general, it is extremely inadequate for deep raids and serious operations at the nodes of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Rumor has it that the ghost stalker never carries a first aid kit with him. Everything heals on him like on a dog. They say that he has an unusual suit that he got on an anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_description_m2">
		<text>The former owner of this thing was a real tourist and, it seems, often went on very difficult, on the verge of human endurance, hiking trips. He knew how to distribute correctly the weight that he carried, and which things to give preference to. The coat pockets and the educated choice of the backpack allow its owner to carry a heavy weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>Stalker suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Ghost suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_name_m2">
		<text>Tourist suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Reinforced stalker suit produced by the gunsmiths of the Freedom faction. It is made up of a medium military bulletproof vest plated with reinforcing zirconium elements which provide good protection from rifle bullets and splinters from medium and long range. The material of the suit consists of two layers: specially treated leather and fabric with asbestos yarn. The suit provides good protection from radiation and various weak anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Guardian of Freedom suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_description">
		<text>Light stalker suit produced by the gunsmiths of the Freedom faction. It consists of a light military bulletproof vest with reinforcing kevlar plates. It can protect from weak weapons. The fabric of the suit is treated with a special mixture which increases anomaly activity resistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_name">
		<text>Wind of Freedom suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Модифицированный комбинезон свободы</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>В комбинезон интегрирована металлическая сетка, защищающая от электрических и магнитных полей. В комплект также включен прибор ночного видения.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>The exoskeleton protects marvelously from bullet and splinter fire, however it lowers mobility. It is vulnerable to armor bullets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton PNB-4UZ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_military_outfit_description">
		<text>Army bulletproof suit is created for carrying out storming operations. Provides an excellent source of protection from bullet and splinter fire without lowering the mobility of the soldier. Vulnerable to armor piercing bullets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_military_outfit_name">
		<text>Army bulletproof suit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This particular bodysuit is designed for carrying out research in the Zone. It has a breathing system with a closed cycle, as well as a built-in system for nullifying the activity of anomalous fields, thanks to which it protects marvelously from anomalies. Very vulnerable due to the weak protection. Has a built-in container for transporting artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Scientific bodysuit</text>
       </string>
	<string id="protection_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>A high-quality overall made of heavy-duty materials based on the Monolit Nauchny suit. Effective protection against radiation and biological anomalies. Resistant to chemically aggressive environments and other harmful to the body effects. The kit also includes a night visiosn device with digital signal filtering and a psi-radiation protection system.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="protection_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Jumpsuit overalls</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice_outfit_description_m2">
		<text>In the jacket is sewn a Kevlar gasket, increasing protection from bullet and fragmentation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice_outfit_name_m2">
		<text>Kevlar Jacket</text>
       </string>
	<string id="military_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Exoskeleton SKAT-10</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Prototype of an army special armored suit-exoskeleton SKAT-10. It is based on the well-proven in the conditions of the Zone. Most likely it is produced by the same enterprise that produces Duty exoskeletons, since the parameters are almost identical.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>Modification of overalls &quot;Monolith&quot;. Like most Monolith creations, the technology is unknown. It is established that the structure includes extraterrestrial materials. They are lighter than their terrestrial counterparts and very well protect against radiation, accelerate metabolism and reflect psy-radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Chernobyl jumpsuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>The Science Suit of Liberty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>Production of the Freedom Group, for scientific research in the zone. Closed-loop protection system, built-in system to suppress abnormal fields. High radiation protection. Bullet protection is still not enough for active combat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Science suit mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>A suit of mercenaries who are in abnormal zones. Closed-loop protection system, built-in system to suppress abnormal fields. Provides good protection against bullet and shrapnel hit, but clearly insufficient for large-scale fighting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_exoskeleton_name">
		<text>Monolith exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_exoskeleton_description">
		<text>The technology of creation is unknown. The material contains inclusions of an unknown metal, the nature of origin is unknown. Surprisingly low weight and high even indicators on all points. Maximum protection from radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_exoskeleton_name">
		<text>Freedom Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_exoskeleton_description">
		<text>The product of the artisans from Freedom. Experimenting with different modifications, after numerous attempts they managed to create a really successful design. The characteristics are comparable to the Duty suit. Work to improve it continues.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_blue_exoskeleton_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton of mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_blue_exoskeleton_description">
		<text>An experimental sample of a Western-made military exoskeleton. This exoskeleton belongs to the third generation. Used by mercenaries. The emphasis is on combat use, abnormal stability is low.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_black_exoskeleton_name">
		<text>Duty Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_black_exoskeleton_description">
		<text>Domestic development of one of the research institutes, especially for the Duty faction. Combat functions prevail, heavy payload. The weight of the suit, however, does not exclude the possibility of running in it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nebo_exo_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton Hunters</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nebo_exo_description">
		<text>The exoskeleton perfectly protects against various abnormal effects, radiation, as well as bites and strokes. Vulnerable to armor-piercing rounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nebo_light_outfit_name">
		<text>Outfit "Hunters"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nebo_light_outfit_description">
		<text>The hunters' lightweight stalker jumpsuit. Light army body armor. It is able to protect against weak weapons. The fabric of the overalls is treated with a special composition that increases resistance to abnormal activity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nebo_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Outfit "Guardian hunt"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nebo_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>The reinforced stalker jumpsuit produced by hunters. Medium army body armor. The material of the suit consists of two layers: specially treated skin and fabric with asbestos floss. Gives good protection against various abnormal influences and radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_soldier_new_name">
		<text>Army suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_soldier_new_description">
		<text>The standard set of soldier's equipment is light army body armor, boots and camouflage. Effectively enough protects against gun bullets and shrapnel. Ineffective against abnormal and other effects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dark_veteran_outfit_name">
		<text>Leather cloak</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dark_veteran_outfit_description">
		<text>It has a little more protection from injuries and fire than a regular jacket. Clothes of "dark" veterans. Protection is extremely insufficient, but comfortable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_master_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit cloak</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_master_outfit_description">
		<text>At first, these cloaks were a hallmark of the Arrow OPG. Now such are the brigadiers of crime. Not a bad bullet resistance... for a cloak made of natural leather.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_name_m2">
		<text>Экзоскелет "NA"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_description_m2">
		<text>Exoskeleton of the future developed by the corporation "New Arsenal".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_battle">
		<text>Helmet «Sphere М12»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_battle_descr">
		<text>A fabric-trimmed aluminum-titanium helmet with pockets for steel armored elements and an armored mask. Usually comes complete with PS3 class body armor for special forces. It is quite popular in the zone thanks to the respirator and built-in night vision device, as well as good head protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_hardhat">
		<text>Steel helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_hardhat_descr">
		<text>A standard army steel helmet. It does not provide protection against anomalies or radiation, but is able to deflect the bullet that came by tangent. Demand in the zone was used only during the first clashes between the factions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_protective">
		<text>Helmet «Protective»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_protective_descr">
		<text>A lightweight helmet with an airtight visor designed to protect the face from some anomalous effects. Judging by the technology, it was developed by the same defense research institute as the SEVA jumpsuit - presumably for use complete with army protective suits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator">
		<text>Respirator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_descr">
		<text>A standard gas mask designed to filter radioactive dust and poisonous substances from the air. It is widely used by both newcomers and veterans of all groups due to its functional irreplaceability. Not equipped with protection from bullets, shrapnel and mechanical influences.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_tactic">
		<text>Tactical helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_tactic_descr">
		<text>A western sample of a tactical helmet devoid of any markings. It is designed to provide the unit commander with as much tactical information as possible when installing the appropriate electronic "stuffing." It has a reinforced design; it is also equipped with multi-layered Kevlar protection, a respirator and night vision device.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
